Dorothy Sears Ainsworth Papers, 1894-1976
Smith College Archives
Dorothy Sears Ainsworth Papers
1916-1975
Ainsworth, Dorothy Sears 1874-1976
RG 42 UUID:c5c214b0-eb57-4f70-9136-e6d724b58cba
50 boxes (21 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
Professor and Director of Physical Education. The papers contain biographical material, speeches, lectures, organizational notes and correspondence, student papers, subject files, publications, photographs, and awards.
Dorothy Sears Ainsworth was born in Moline, Illinois to Harry and Stella (Davidson) Ainsworth on March 8, 1894. Growing up in Moline exposed Dorothy to a large and growing immigrant population, which would encourage her international work in physical education in later life. The local industries included the John Deere Plow Company and Moline Plow Company. Her father was a very active sportsman, who participated in local tournaments, and her mother was active in organizational work.
In 1912, she joined her sister Sarah at Smith College living at 8 Bedford Terrace before moving to Chapin House for her second year. During her time at Smith, Ainsworth was involved in theater and sports, especially basketball. In May of 1916 with a degree in history, she returned to Moline to pay back her community for her education; there she taught physical education to high school girls. In 1919, Dorothy joined the Smith College Relief Unit in Grecourt, France where she worked in the transportation department, keeping the vehicles in running condition. In 1921, Dorothy returned to Smith College as an instructor in the Department of Hygiene and Physical Education. She taught basketball and dance. Later she went to Teachers College in Columbia University to obtain a formal education in physical education. She graduated with a Masters in Art degree in 1925, taught one year at Skidmore College before becoming the Director of Physical Education at Smith College in 1926--a position she would hold for 34 years. In 1930, Ainsworth was the fourth woman and the tenth person to receive a Doctorate from Columbia University with a specialization in physical education.
As Director of Physical Education at Smith College, Ainsworth devoted energy in developing an undergraduate curriculum which contributed to students' well being and development so that they could live a richer, more abundant life. She increased the number of different sporting opportunities offered to students from 6 in 1926 to 14 in 1960. She increased Smith's athletic facilities: adding riding stables, squash courts, an ice hockey rink, four hockey fields, two soccer fields, 26 tennis courts, three fairways and holes for golf, ten archery ranges, and 4 shells for crew by 1935. In 1932 the New York Herald Tribune noted that winter term enrollment was almost 100% with 1,738 out of 1,832 students enrolled in sports activities. In 1940, she created a graduate course for training teachers in physical education.
While at Smith, Ainsworth was also very active in the larger arena of physical education for women, belonging and participating in numerous associations, congresses, and conferences. The Association of Directors of Physical Education for Women (ADPEW), started in 1916, was the forerunner of the Eastern Association for Physical Education of College Women. Dorothy joined the ADPEW when she became director at Smith and brought the Association to Smith College in 1931; Dorothy served terms as president during her years of service to both organizations. She was also very active in the National Association for Physical Education for College Women of the United States (NAPECW)-serving as chair on many important committees including organizing chairman for the first International Congress on Physical Education for Girls and Women which was held in Copenhagen 1949. At the second Congress in Paris, an Association was formed by the heads of the delegations and, instead of having a continuing committee; they formed The International Association of Physical Education and Sports for Girls and Women (IAPESGW).
She continued working with and establishing contacts world-wide. She represented the National Education Association at the World Organization of Teaching Profession which was the forerunner of the World Confederation of Organizations of the Teaching Profession (WCOTP). She was also a U.S. Delegate to the Pan American Congress of Physical Education in 1950 where she presented a paper on the results of the women's Copenhagen Congress. After years of travel, research and conversation with physical education teachers and directors world-wide, Dorothy coordinated, spearheaded, and helped write the constitution creating the International Council on Health, Physical Education and Recreation (ICHPER) as she had with the IAPESGW.
Ainsworth earned numerous awards and honors. She was the first woman to receive France's highest award in sports - the Cravate de Commandeur de l'Ordre du Merite Sportif. In 1970, His Majesty the Emperor of Japan granted Dorothy "The Fourth Class of the Order of the Precious Crown" in recognition of her assistance to the women of Japan in the field of physical education. The American Alliance for Health, Physical education and Recreation presented Dorothy with a "Presidential Service Award" in 1974 for her contributions to international physical education, as did The National Council of Women of the United States with their "Woman of Conscience Award" in 1968.
Dorothy Sears Ainsworth, Professor Emeritus of Physical Education at Smith College, passed away on December 2, 1976 at the age of 82 in a nursing home in her home town of Moline Illinois.
The Dorothy Sears Ainsworth Papers contain significant documentation of her involvement with Smith College as a student, alumnae, professor, and with the Smith College Relief Unit. The bulk of the collection rests in Ainsworth's professional correspondence as she created various congresses and organizations to further communication about women's physical education. Also included are newspaper clippings, press releases, photographs, programs, as well as histories and constitutions of various organizations.
The collection also has some photographs that denote women's physical education costumes around the world and histories of various sports including pamphlets showing colonial games.
The collection is divided into the following series: Biography, Smith College, Correspondence, Organizations, Conferences, Writings, Subject Files, Photographs, Awards, Scrapbooks, and Audio-Visual.
Note: The National Association for Physical Education for College Women of the United States (NAPECW) created the first Congress in Copenhagen 1949. At the second Congress in Paris, the heads of the delegations formed an Association and they decided that instead of having a continuing committee, they would form The International Association of Physical Education and Sports for Girls and Women (IAPESGW). This group continued the meeting of Congresses every four years.
This collection is organized into eight series:
Series I. Biography
Series II. Smith College
Series III. Correspondence
Series IV. Organizations
Series V. Conferences
Series VI. Writings
Series VII. Subject files, A-Z
Series VIII. Awards, photographs and scrapbooks
Series IX. Audio-visual
The papers are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
The Dorothy Sears Ainsworth Papers were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- RG 12 War Service, World War I, 1914-18 Smith College Relief Unit
- RG 80 Phi Kappa Society
- RG 52 Physical Education Scrapbooks
- RG 100 C710a-C710h - 8 Audiotapes
- Series I. Biography
  - Dorothy S. Ainsworth: Her life, professional career and contributions to physical education, by Hazel Peterson-Dissertation (vol.1 and 2) 1968 (Box 1)
  - Dorothy S. Ainsworth: Her life, professional career and contributions to physical education, by Hazel Peterson-published Moscow, Idaho 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ainsworth Biography (Box 2)
  - Smith Biography (Box 2)
  - Trips and Itineraries (Box 2)
  - News Clippings (Box 2)
  - Obituaries 1975 (Box 2)
  - Father's Trip to the Black Hills 1885 (Box 2)
  - Northampton Life (Box 2)
- Series II. Smith College
  - Alpha Society and Phi Kappa Psi 1915-16 (Box 3)
  - Class of 1916 (Box 3)
    - Silver Jubilee Class Book 1941 (Box 3)
    - 45th Reunion 1961 (Box 3)
    - 50th Reunion 1966 (Box 3)
    - 51th Reunion 1967 (Box 3)
    - 52th Reunion 1968 (Box 3)
    - 53th Reunion 1969 (Box 3)
    - 54th Reunion 1970 (Box 3)
    - 55th Reunion 1971 (Box 3)
    - 56th Reunion 1972 (Box 3)
    - 57th Reunion 1973 (Box 4)
    - 58th Reunion 1974 (Box 4)
    - 59th Reunion 1975 (Box 4)
    - 60th Reunion 1976 (Box 4)
    - 75th Reunion 1991 (Box 4)
    - Financial Reports 1940-73 (Box 4)
    - Class Letters 1962-75 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous undated (Box 4)
  - Alumnae Associates of the Smith College Course in Physical Education (Box 4)
  - Poetry (Box 4)
  - Press Releases (Box 4)
  - Retirement Banquet 1960 (Box 4)
  - Sports Policies (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - A-Z 1950-74 (Box 5)
    - Mary Elund 1966-76 (Box 5)
    - Georgia Farnsworth 1966-71 (Box 5)
    - Miriam Haseltine 1971-75 (Box 5)
    - Zoe Hawkins 1975-76 (Box 5)
    - Violet McIvor 1966-76 (Box 5)
    - Rosamond Praeger 1966-76 (Box 5)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Personal/Professional 1912-13 (Box 6)
  - Personal/Professional 1946-47 (Box 6)
  - Personal/Professional 1951-57 (Box 6)
  - Ainsworth Scholarship 1975 (Box 6)
  - Around the World Trip (1 of 2) 1956-57 (Box 6)
  - Around the World Trip (2 of 2) 1956-57 (Box 6)
  - Typed Copies of Written Letters 1956-57 (Box 6)
  - Brazil, University of-Dance Group 1951 (Box 6)
  - Christmas Cards 1956-68 (Box 6)
  - General 1956 (Box 6)
  - International Congress of Physical Education for Women 1949 (Box 7)
  - NATO 1950s (Box 7)
  - Renaissance and Early Sports/Games Booklets 1618-49 (Box 7)
  - A 1948-73 (Box 7)
  - B 1949-70 (Box 7)
  - C 1948-75 (Box 7)
  - Commission on the Education of Women 1953 (Box 7)
  - D 1949-75 (Box 7)
  - Duncan, E. 1947-55 (Box 7)
  - E 1950-66 (Box 7)
  - F 1949-61 (Box 7)
  - G 1949-72 (Box 8)
  - H 1948-71 (Box 8)
  - I-J 1947-61 (Box 8)
  - K 1949-65 (Box 8)
  - L 1951-71 (Box 8)
  - Mc 1951-72 (Box 8)
  - M 1948-73 (Box 8)
  - N 1951-61 (Box 9)
  - O 1951-59 (Box 9)
  - P 1951-73 (Box 9)
  - Plans for Chinese Physical Education Institute-Hui-Ching La 1948-50 (Box 9)
  - R 1948-74 (Box 9)
  - S 1949-72 (Box 10)
  - T 1949-73 (Box 10)
  - U-V 1948-64 (Box 10)
  - W 1949-65 (Box 10)
  - Z 1954-73 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1951-67 (Box 10)
- Series IV. Organizations
  - American Academy of Physical Education (AAPE) (Box 10)
    - AAPE 1950s-60s (Box 10)
    - AAPE (1 of 2) (Box 10)
    - AAPE (2 of 2) (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Members 1953-60 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-Las Vegas 1967 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-St. Louis 1968 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-Boston 1969 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-Seattle 1970 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-Detroit 1971 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-Houston 1972 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Conventions-Minneapolis 1973 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Correspondence-A-Z 1951-72 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Reports, Newsletters 1969-73 (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Commission on International Relations (Box 11)
    - AAPE-Miscellaneous 1954-72, (1 photograph) (Box 11)
  - American Association for Health, Physical Education and Recreation (AAHPER) (Box 11)
    - AAHPER-American College of Sports Medicine 1969-71 (Box 11)
    - AAHPER-Annual Reports 1968-69 (Box 11)
    - AAHPER-Board of Directors Meetings 1949-72 (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees: Administrative Resource Committee (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees: Archives Advisory Committee (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees: Committee on International Exchange of Persons (CIEP)-Pamphlets and Statements (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees-CIEP-Conference-Board of Associated Research Councils (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees-CIEP-Conference-3rd National (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Committees-CIEP-Correspondence 1950-62 (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-International Congress on the Essentials of Physical Education for Youth Connecticut Valley Congress, (CVC) Northampton, MA-Accounts 1954 (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-A 1953-55 (Box 12)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-B 1953-55 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-C 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-D 1953-60 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-E-F 1953-55 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-G 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-H-I 1953-55 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-J-K 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-L 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-M 1953-55 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-N-O 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-P 1952-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-R 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-S 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-T-Z 1953-55 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Correspondence-Miscellaneous 1953-54 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Delegates 1954 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-News Clippings 1954 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Papers 1954 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Photographs 1954 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Preparation 1954 (Box 13)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-CVC-Programs 1954 (Box 14)
    - AAPHER-Conventions-CVC-Resolutions for UNESCO and WHO 1954 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Dallas 1950 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Detroit 1951 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Washington 1958 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Miami 1961 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Chicago 1966 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Boston 1969 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Seattle 1970 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Detroit 1971 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Houston 1972 (Box 14)
    - AAHPER-Conventions-Minneapolis 1973 (Box 14)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Form Letters 1948-66 (Box 14)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Memorandum 1949-72 (Box 14)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-A-B 1947-74 (Box 14)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Rachel Bryant 1951-57 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Rachel Bryant 1958-72 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-C 1950-72 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Raymond A. Ciszek 1965-74 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Frederick A. Colwell 1959-61 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-D 1950-71 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-E-F 1947-72 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-G-H 1950-63 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-I-J 1950-72 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-K 1951-63 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-L 1951-70 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-M 1950-72 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-N-O 1949-62 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-P-R 1949-66 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-S-T 1947-72 (Box 15)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Carl A. Troester 1949-70 (Box 16)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-U-Z 1947-64 (Box 16)
    - AAPHER-Correspondence-Miscellaneous 1950-72 (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-Division of Girls and Women's Sports (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-Division of Men's Athletics (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-Eastern District Association (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-Health Education Division (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-History (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-International Relations Council (IRC)-Conference on International Relations 1950s-60s (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Historical Overview (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Minutes 1948-71 (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Newsletter 1947-70 (Box 16)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Operating Code and Organization 1947-72 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Reports 1960-70 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-IRC-Reports (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-Joint Council on International Affairs (JCIA)-Beginnings 1950 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA-Codes, Charts, Purposes (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1951 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1952 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1953 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1954 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1955 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1956 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1957 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1958 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1959 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-JICA 1960 (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-Monograph (Box 17)
    - AAHPER-News (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Organization and Constitution (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Physical Education Division (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Physical Education Theoretical Structure Project (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Policy Statements (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Presidents' Reports 1950-51 (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Publications (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Recreation Division (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-School Health Division (Box 18)
    - AAHPER-Selection on Women's Athletics (Box 18)
  - American Association for Physical Education of College Women-1st World Letters 1948 (Box 18)
  - American Association for Physical Education of College Women-Mailing List for World Letters 1948 (Box 18)
  - American College of Sports Medicine 1955 (Box 18)
  - American Council on Education 1950s (Box 18)
  - American National Council for Health Education of the Public (Box 18)
  - American Youth Hostels, Inc. 1969 (Box 18)
  - California Association for Health Physical Education and Recreation 1969-70 (Box 18)
  - Canadian Association for Health Physical Education and Recreation 1951, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Congress of European American Associations (CEAA) 1953 (Box 18)
  - Eastern Society of Directors of Physical Education for College Women-Meetings 1920s-40s, 1960s (Box 18)
  - Eastern Society of Directors of Physical Education for College Women-Programs 1927-36 (Box 18)
  - Eastern Society of Directors of Physical Education for College Women 1940s (Box 18)
  - Girls Clubs of America 1951-52 (Box 18)
  - Improving the Teaching of World Affairs 1950s-60s (Box 19)
  - International Assembly of Women-International Women's Day (Box 19)
  - International Association of Physical Education and Sports for Girls and Women (IAPESGW) (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Ballots (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Constitution (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Addresses 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Archives 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence-Booth, Olive 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence-Pribitzer, Helena 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence-McCouchie, Lorna 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence-Romero-Brest, Mrs. Henrique de 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence-Endres, Steffi 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Correspondence-Dr. Trittremmel 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW Congress-1949-Correspondence to American Delegates 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW Congress-1949-Correspondence-World Letters 1948 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Foreign Relations (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Film Suggestions (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Honorary Committee Members (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Marsh Tour 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Members 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Notes and Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Program 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Progress Report 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Report 1950, (1 photograph) (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-Speakers and Helpers Suggestions 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-U.N. Members 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1949-U.S. Delegates 1949 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1953-Paris 1953 (Box 19)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1953-Program 1953 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1953-Reports and Speeches by Ainsworth 1953 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1957 (1 of 5) 1957 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1957-Group XV (2 of 5) 1957, (1 photograph) (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1957-Program (3 of 5) 1957 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1957-Proposed Constitution (4 of 5)1957 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1957-Speeches (5 of 5) 1957 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Citations 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Daily News 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Form Letters 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Forms, Information Sheets, Programs, Printed Material 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Funds and Accts. 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Delegates 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Minutes, Reports 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Papers 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Questionnaire I 1961 (Box 20)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Questionnaire II 1961 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1961-Teaching Positions 1961 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1965 1965 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1969-Tokyo 1969 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1973-Teheran 1973 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Congress-1973-Jerusalem Workshop in Israeli Folklore and Dance 1973 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-A 1948-72 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Adevoso, Carmen 1969-72 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Amylong, Tora 1954-64 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Aquino, Francisca 1953-61 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-B 1948-69 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Bachman, Lydia 1947-60 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Beltrao, Fernanda 1960-64 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Bertram, Agnete 1950-64 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Betts, Edith 1969-75 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-C 1952-62 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Chavez, R. Consuelo 1954-62 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Cobar, Natalia 1953-61 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Colson, Phyllis 1954-60 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Crosslin, Hiawatha 1950-55 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-D 1948-69 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Deach, Dorothy 1958-60 (Box 21)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-De Huelin, Maria de Miranda 1950-62 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-De Ribeyro, Josefa Lora 1953-62 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-De Storek, Marta Lora 1953-61, (photographs) (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Diem, Liselott 1952-56 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Diem, Liselott 1957-61 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Diem, Liselott 1964-73 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Dodd, Barbara 1953-63 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-E 1957-61 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Eyquem, Marie Therese 1947-52 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Eyquem, Marie Therese 1953-56 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Eyquem, Marie Therese 1957-61 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-F 1948-73 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Foster, Ruth 1951-61 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-G 1947-64 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Gotta, Adriena 1953-64 (Box 22)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-H 1948-69 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Hazelton, Helen 1951-57 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Hazelton, Helen 1958 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-I 1951-61 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-J 1948-59 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-K, L 1953-68 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-M 1948-73 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-McDonald, Kathleen 1952-73 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Matsumoto, Chiyoe 1969-71 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-N 1948-62 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Nel, Isabelle 1952-71 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-O 1950-62 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-P 1948 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Pirnia, Ezat 1957-73 (Box 23)
    - IAPESGW-Correspondence-Plewes, Doris 1950-73 (Box 23)